All done.
Pitching a tent's harder than I thought.
Hey! Hitoma!
If you're not busy, help me make food!
Usami! Don't point knives at people!
Shut up!
Get over here or I'll crush you!
What? Crush?!
I just heard you say the word "crush."
Has Mr. Rei finally admitted
to having a crush on me?!
You're annoying me, Karin,
so you help out with the barbecue, too.
What?!
I don't mind, since Mr. Rei's here.
Squeak! I can't handle onions!
What do you need me to do?
Tobari, start preparing the mess tin.
Isaki wants to help make rice
in the mess tin, too!
Episode 8
The Misanthrope and the Magic for Peace and Quiet
I can still eat more!
Clean up once you're done eating.
That was delicious!
Glad you liked it, Macchan!
Isaki had tons of fun, too!
Mr. Rei, would you care for seconds?
Thanks, but I'm too full to eat any more.
No need to hold back, Mr. Rei!
When I serve you rice like this,
it feels like we're newlyweds...
Oh, what joy!
No, I really can't eat more.
We're not done just yet!
Marshmallows
Ta-da!
Nothing to end a barbecue
like some marshmallows!
For real? Awesome!
Yeah, let's roast 'em!
I want some, too.
Mr. Hitoma, try a s'more.
S'more?
You take a gooey, melted marshmallow,
and put it between some salty crackers
with chocolate inside.
Whoa, there's no way that's not good!
Mmm! It's so sweet and yummy!
Not gonna have any?
Sensitive tongue.
Karin-rin, can I try
lifting your boobs up?
Isaki, you sound like a perv.
What?
You don't get hyped
when you see some huge milkers?
I don't mind at all.
Score! Thanks, Karin-rin!
Wanna feel Isaki's up in exchange?
The hell's that about?
Thanks, Isaki!
For what?!
Not gonna get in, Neneko?
No, thanks. Don't like water.
Too bad, it feels great.
Hate feeling all soggy.
But you'll still keep us company?
Uchami. Let's see who can
last longer in the sauna.
I won't be part of such a pointless game.
Oh? Is someone scared to lose?
Heh heh.
Machi, even your taunts
are dumb and childish.
A shooting star? Should have made a wish.
Still awake, Mr. Hitoma?
You didn't go to sleep, Haneda?
There was somewhere I wanted to go.
Wanna come along?
A shrine?
You see, this is
where this school first started.
Started?
At first, Shiro ran
the school out of this shrine.
Shiro? You mean the principal?
That brings me back.
It all began when a dryad said
she wanted to become human.
I turned her human without thinking,
and sent her off into the human world.
But it didn't work out very well.
She didn't understand
how human manners or culture worked.
That's when the idea came to me.
I just needed to prepare them first
before I turned them human.
That's how the school started.
What happened to that dryad?
She couldn't fit into human society.
But she's still here at our school.
You know the cherry tree?
This is the center of the barrier.
It forms the core of this school.
The core?
Yep.
I thought it'd be good
for you to learn about this place.
As thanks for tagging along,
let me show you something nice.
Did you make a wish?
A wish.
My wish was for your wish to come true.
I wished I could learn to like humans.
I can't tell anyone
about such a stupid wish.
Art Room
Kurosawa. What's that?
A self-portrait?
Yes.
Do you like art?
It's fine.
What?
Um, do you like paintings that are black?
They're fine.
I see.
Don't like colors.
They deviate from what's normal.
What's this? Is that Mr. Hitoma I see?
Mr. Emoto.
Did you come to check in on Kurosawa?
Oh, yes.
Mr. Hitoma, ever wanted to try modeling?
Excuse me?
Kurosawa, why don't you try
having Mr. Hitoma model for you?
He wears black, so sure.
You heard her.
Mr. Hitoma, you'll be our live
model every Monday from now on.
What?! Just like that?!
Kurosawa's already agreed to it.
Right?
You won't?
Please.
A/V Room
All right.
Let's begin our special training program.
Taught by the director herself...
Today's course will be "Humans
and Humanoid Species."
Humanoid?
Werewolf
Mermaid
The main examples would be werewolves
like Isaki and mermaids like Kyoka.
Yuki-onna
Oh, yuki-onna like Yuki
and crow tengu like the principal as well.
Crow Tengu
You mean species whose original forms
are close to that of humans?
That's right, Mr. Hitoma.
You're quick on the uptake.
I have a question I'd like to ask.
Hm? What is it?
Do aliens, inter-dimensional
sliders, and espers exist?
Sure do.
They do?!
So, why this training all of a sudden?
There's a humanoid species visiting us,
so I figured you should brush up.
Visiting us? Is it an alien?
Nope, a witch.
A witch?!
I wanted to introduce you to said witch.
Would that be all right?
What?
She's Neneko Kurosawa's guardian.
What?!
She can be a bit of a handful,
but I'm sure you'll be fine.
Director's Office
Long time, no see. How's it been?
Oh, Lady Shiranui!
It's so boring without you around!
You're so wonderfully tiny in this form.
Like an adorable infant.
Thanks.
Is this her homeroom teacher?
That's right. Call him Mr. Hitoma.
Oh?
She's showing zero interest.
Let me introduce you.
This is Alice Medea, her guardian.
Hello. I'm Rei Hitoma,
Neneko Kurosawa's homeroom teacher.
Did she end up being named Neneko?
You came up with
a great name, Lady Shiranui.
Thanks.
Lady Shiranui, how much longer
are you going to stay in this dull place?
With these tacky, loud-mouthed tengu.
Pardon?
You came to me for advice
when you started the school,
so I thought you were
going to stay by my side.
I told you I was going to
stick around here from the start.
But you really helped me
out back then, Alice.
Thanks.
I love you!
On what business have you come here again?
What? The biggest reason
is I wanted to see Lady Shiranui.
And since I'm here, I wanted to ask my
kitty's homeroom teacher how she's doing.
There you have it.
How do you think Neneko's
doing, Mr. Hitoma?
Kurosawa's doing just fine.
I do warn her about
falling asleep all the time.
But it hasn't affected her grades,
which are top of the class.
I see.
It's best that she leave me before long,
so turn her human as soon as you can.
That all depends on Neneko.
Miss Alice, why do you
want Kurosawa to be human?
I don't know if it's from
being around me for so long,
but she's started to gain magical power.
Good thing I noticed just
before it was too late.
Too late?
We can't have her wielding magic,
so I reached out to Lady Shiranui,
who agreed to take her in.
Why can't she wield magic?
If she exceeds a certain level of
magical power, she'll cease to be a cat.
I believe you call it
a nekomata around here?
Nekomata?
It'd be a real hassle if that happened.
Nekomata are but shadows
of their beastly selves.
They can't control their own magic,
and attack people against their will.
Nekomata
Do you think she could live
with herself like that?
Which is why, to ensure her
magical power stays below the limit,
I figured I could have Lady
Shiranui turn her into a human.
I can't turn Alice down.
Neneko agreed to as well,
so I let her enroll.
Kurosawa agreed to it?
What's more, as long
as she's inside the barrier,
her physical body will stop growing,
so she won't gain any magic.
Um, can I tell Kurosawa
about our meeting, Miss Alice?
Huh? No... Sure...
Which is it?
I don't want her to think
I'm an uncool mom who's clingy!
But I'm sure she's sensed my magic
and figured out I'm here.
In that case, I guess it should be fine...
Alice, weren't you here today to see me?
Yes! That's right!
Listen up, human.
Feel free to tell my kitty all
about my visit.
Oh, sure.
What? Is she just a big ol' softy?
It's about time I get going.
I'm planning to stay in the area
for a while, so I'll be back soon.
Bye, Lady Shiranui.
Yeah. Stay in touch.
What'd you think of Alice?
I had my reservations, but I'm glad
to see how much she cares about Kurosawa.
Right? She's a funny one.
Especially how she
doesn't seem to realize it.
Art Room
So it was my mistress...
I knew it was her magic.
Hey, Kurosawa.
Can I ask you something?
Kurosawa, do you want to be human?
If my mistress wills it.
I'm not asking about Miss Alice.
Do you want to be human?
I don't know.
But since I'm... not normal...
What do you think being normal means?
Whatever my mistress wills.
That's what's normal.
Mr. Hitoma.
Do you think colors are necessary?
Huh? Colors?
It's normal for everyone else
to use lots of colors.
My mistress also...
I like your art, Kurosawa.
Your art may lack color,
but you come through clearly in it.
You and I may see in different colors,
but that difference
doesn't mean you're wrong.
That's why I don't think colors
are an absolute must.
I dodged that!
Shiranui High
Yes? This is Hitoma speaking.
Oh, Mr. Hitoma.
Kurosawa attempted an escape
from the barrier.
What?
Luckily, we caught
her in time, so she's safe.
Mr. Hitoma, can you come
to the principal's office now?
I'll be right there.
Principal's Office
Why'd you try to escape?
I wanted to... erase the colors.
Mr. Hitoma.
I don't want to become human.
So you broke school rules,
hoping to be expelled?
Yes.
But why an escape?
Is there somewhere you were trying to go?
Because...
I thought my mistress
would come and get me.
Miss Alice?
Yes.
Why don't you show
yourself already, Alice?
What?
Can't keep your mouth shut, tengu?
I can't really blame him this time around.
Mistress...
A lowly cat like you has got
some nerve summoning me here.
So? What will you do?
If you go back with me, your only
future will be turning into a monster.
I studied up.
Huh? What?
I studied black magic in search...
of a way to remain in control of myself.
A way to control yourself?
Did you find one?
I found nothing.
So it was pointless.
Still, I... don't want to be human.
So...
I was hoping you would...
put an end to it all.
What?! Do you realize what you're saying?!
I do.
You rescued me. Raised me.
Gave me your magic.
And now I'm here.
Which is why...
Alice.
It's your responsibility.
And if I refuse?
You can't.
Seriously?
Didn't you say you were fine
with being human?
Mr. Hitoma taught me.
I don't need to abide
by what you will of me as normal.
You're all I need.
You're all I ever wanted.
Why are you making me do this?
The color black is all I'll ever know.
What? I don't know what that means.
With a little more time,
I might have figured something out.
So you could deal with it
if you just had more time?
If I could control her magic,
and create a suitable vessel to hold it...
Three years, then.
You have three years.
I'll maintain Neneko
at her current magical level.
Can you figure something out in that time?
I-I can!
Neneko?
Does that mean...
I might be able to stay
with Alice forever?
Yes, if everything goes well.
I... want to stay with Alice.
Then you'll have to work hard.
Lady Shiranui.
How exactly will you stop her
from gaining magic?
There are two methods.
The first is to lend her my ring,
and have her learn to control her magic.
The second is to have her live in
the shrine in the forest and learn there.
I suggest the latter,
since I can lend my support.
The shrine?
Ugh, I don't want to
be indebted to a tengu!
I would rather not as well.
But since it's Lady Shiranui's proposal,
I'll go along with it.
So? What do you think?
Fine...
Even if it means being
beholden to that tengu...
In that case...
Neneko Kurosawa, you are hereby dismissed.
Ugh, this shrine's a mess.
Must you be so rude all the time, Alice?
Can I use magic on this
building? Is it magic-free?
Why does it sound like
you're talking about smoking?
Due to the barrier,
you can't use magic on the building.
Instead, Mr. Hitoma will be
making visits as a custodian.
Do a good job cleaning this place.
Sure thing.
I don't know if I should
still call you Kurosawa...
But I saw you finished that portrait of me
in the art room a while back.
That drawing's been long complete.
But it seems Kurosawa didn't
want to put an end to it.
Was she fussing over the details?
Or perhaps she took
a liking to you, Mr. Hitoma.
I guess we'll never know,
since she's left the school.
Kurosawa.
Thank you.
Next Episode:
The Misanthrope and the Heart's Deepest Desire